this problem has given us
two pieces of code and we're going to
examine them
each and determine what the program will
output
so looking at the first piece of code on
line one
a local variable x is initialized and it
references
the integer zero we then invoke the
times method
on the integer three and we've passed
the block to this times method
so ruby's going to iterate through this
block three times
the code on line three may look a little
bit confusing if you haven't seen it
before
this is shorthand
for x equals x plus one
so this operation here on line three is
reassignment
we are reassigning x to the value of x
plus 1. so on our first iteration
through this block
x will be reassigned to the integer 1
then 2 and then 3. then ruby stops
iterating through this block
and our program execution reaches line
five
on line five we invoke the put us method
to
output x because we know that we have
iterated through this block three times
incrementing the integer referenced by x
we expect that x now references the
integer three
and that's what we expect to see when we
output x on line five
so let's run our code and see that
and we see three as expected
so let's take a look at the second piece
of code we were given
this code is a little bit different we
have two variables
y and x y is initialized on line one
and it references zero again we invoke
the times method on the integer 3 and
pass it a block
within the block we are going to
reassign y
to y plus 1 each time we iterate through
that's the behavior we saw with the
variable x in our previous piece of code
then on line 4 you can see that we
initialize a local variable
x and we point it at the same value
referenced by y
so as we iterate through this block
three times y will be reassigned to one
two and then three when the code on line
four
runs x will also be assigned to those
integers
so when program execution reaches line
six and we
output x you may expect to see three
however there is a problem here because
unlike y
x was initialized within the block
blocks create an inner scope variables
initialized within an inner scope
are not available in an outer scope
on line six we expect that ruby will
raise an error
we run our code and we see this error we
can see that the problem occurred on
line
6 and the error message tells us we have
an undefined
local variable or method x
because x was initialized in that inner
scope ruby cannot see what x is on line
six
however we can output y and if we run
our code we'll see that
the difference is that y was initialized
on line 1
in the outer scope interscopes
can access variables initialized in the
outer scope
however the outer scope cannot access
variables initialized
in the inner scope in order to output x
on line
6 we would need to initialize x in the
outer scope
so if we initialize x on line two
and run our code again our code now runs
without error
and is able to output x from outside the
block
looking back at our first snippet of
code which i've pasted on lines 8
through 12
you can see the same behavior there x
was initialized
on line 8 in the outer scope
it was accessible inside the inner scope
of the block on line 10
and was successfully output on line 12
in the outer scope
you